All right then,
we’re headed off to the market.
We should grab some berries
and mushrooms in the forest, too.
Whoa!
They’ve got some rare vegetables!
We should go Pokémon Battling!
Okay!
Then, I’ll...
Liko!
Come here with me!
Hm?
It says this café’s doing
a Metamon collab menu!
Squishy Meta-Mochi Parfaits!
Shall we?
Ooh!
How cute!
Time to dig in!
Mmmm!
Squishy-squishy!
You two seem to have
some nice squishies.
Ah, I am no shady individual.
You look pretty shady to me.
In what way?
But that aside...
Those squishy-squishies...
May I have the honor of
squish-squishing them?!
Huh?
Sure, totally fine.
Huh?!
Right, Metamon?
Ooh! Your generosity is
greatly appreciated!
Then, for the touch test.
Ooooh!
This is the highest class of squishiness,
attainable only by Squipokés beloved by their trainers!
And now for you!
Do excuse me!
I won’t overstep boundaries.
But please,
allow me to ask you this.
Are you two...
...at all interested in Squipokacts?
Huh?
What?
Ready, set, and... GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Put our palms together, raise them high, and let our lights unite
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
In rain, gales, or even blizzards
We can laugh together as friends
All of the gaps in the Index
let’s fill them in bit by bit
If you’re trying to be someone else
Don’t think like that
You’re fine just as you are
Don’t lose yourself
Recollect on what’s in your pocket
This is what makes us strong
A heartfelt bond that will never fade
Ready, set, and...
GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Let’s fly, higher and higher!
It’s fine to make mistakes
just rest your wings
When you’ve caught your breath
you can fly off once more!
Come along with us, oh-oh
Voltteccers
Pass the endlessly turning seasons,
and venture into brand-new skies
Squishy Pokémon! When the Squish Gets Squisher, It's Squish Time!!
I see this Meta-Mochi’s fame
was well-earned, after all!
Mmmm!
Another good squish today.
My Squipokacts are progressing well.
Um... So, what’s this “Squipokacts” thing?
Ah, of course.
Allow me to explain.
“Squipokacts” refers to doing
squishy Pokémon-admiring activities.
It’s short for “Squipoké Activities.”
During my days as a salaryman in Hiun City,
when I was feeling crushed beneath my myriad stresses...
...I found squishy Pokémon in my time of need!
And Squipokacts, too!
Ah...
Squipokacts give me
the energy to live on!
So basically you love squishies,
right, old man Yakata?
Yes. After reflecting on my desire
for squishies to be as close to me as possible,
I opted for this spec.
I see!
Huh? You know what he’s getting at?
Nah, not even a little.
But just look at ‘em all and see...
They look... pretty happy!
Right?
But aren’t they
kind of squeezing you?
Are you okay in there?
More than okay!
This pressure is the greatest bliss!
To a Squisher,
this can only be seen as a reward!
Bliss...
I see!
Do you understand
what I’m feeling?
Umm... Probably!
Maybe it’s like when I’m petting Masquernya
and I think “I’m so happy.”
Pre! Cise! Ly! Cor! Rect!
Ooh! Miracle collab squishy,
welcome and hello there!
Mm-hm, squishy, aren’t we?
Mm-hm...
Ah!
Excuse me!
I lost track of myself!
To get back to business,
would you be at all interested in Squipokacts—
I am!
Ooh!
Liko, let’s do it!
Squipokacts with the old man!
Hmm... Right!
We’ve still got free time.
I’m glad to hear it!
The truth is, I’m in this city...
...because my Squipokacts friends
informed me...
...that it’s home to spots where
many rare squishy Pokémon appear!
You’ve got friends...
So then...
Let’s squishy-squishy!
Squishy-squishy!
The first rare squishy Pokémon is...
Goronya.
Goronya?
I don’t think that’s squishy at all!
I thought so too,
but one squish is worth a thousand words!
Immediately after
their yearly shedding,
Goronya are apparently
exquisitely squishy!
But don’t they harden back up
immediately after shedding...?
Indeed! So the chances for
a Goronya-squishing are exceedingly slim!
I must not allow that chance
to slip away!
Then we’ll have to go
to where Goronya shed.
Mm-hm.
And through evaluating past data,
weather patterns, and so on and so forth,
I have already confirmed that today’s
Goronya-shedding index is nearly one hundred percent.
Amazing! You’re kinda smart!
It’s a Goronya—!
There was one!
Ooh!
Could it be?
It’s sheddi—
Whoa!
A squish chance arrives!
Not good! It spotted us!
Aww...
M... My rare squish...
Are you trying to console me?
Ahh... That calms me down...
Thank you, everyone!
It was my fault
we missed the squish chance,
and for that I am dearly sorry.
What’s that?
An apologem for Goronya.
As they say,
“beloved squishies call for good manners.”
I don’t know
if I’ll ever return here...
But I’m sorry for the disturbance.
I kinda thought he was just a weirdo grown-up,
but he’s actually polite.
He really does adore squishy Pokémon,
doesn’t he?
Yeah! But Navi wanted
to squish a Goronya...
Actually, so did I...
Whoa-haha! It’s all squishy!
Ooh? Can I try?
You’re right!
Huh?
You want to let me squish you too,
Masquernya?
It’s so squishy!
The next rare squishy Pokémon is...
Shellder.
Wait, aren’t Shellder hard, too?
“A wise Squipoké hides its squish!”
I hear Shellder’s innards
are incredibly squishy!
Metamon!
Huh?
There’s a Shellder here!
Ooh!
Looks like we made it mad.
Does this mean a battle,
and no way to stop it?
Possibly.
Stop it!
Huh?
A Squisher must never squrden
a Squipoké by their Squipokacts!
What’s a squrden?
There were so many sibilants
that I didn’t get any of that!
It means “burden.”
In any case! We must not anger or frighten
the applicable Pokémon for our mere squish wish!
This is a strict rule
that a Squisher must never break!
You have rules, huh...?
Are you interested?
Then let me give you
these Squisher-Rules Karuta.
Huh? What is it?
“Squisher-Rules Karuta”?
Original karuta manufactured
at my own expense.
In total, they depict one hundred and eight Squisher Rules,
so you can learn them as you play...
Huh?
Shellder’s gone!
What the—?!
We missed a squish again, huh?
I have twice done
something unforgivable.
This is hardly enough
for a full apology, but...
Huh? We get apologems?
Have a go at Namakobushi tossing.
Namakobushi tossing?
Oh, I’ve heard of that!
I think... it’s a part-time job
they do in the Alola Region, right?
It’s the act of returning
washed-up Namakobushi to the sea.
That sounds crazy fun!
I’ll do it, I’ll do it!
You mustn’t merely toss it!
You must toss it while feeling
Namakobushi’s squishiness!
Got it!
Wow! It’s all squishy!
That’s not enough.
Squish it more!
Okay!
More!
More, I say!
Okay!
Now!
O... kay!
Th-That was fun!
We Squishers are not the only ones
to find it fun.
Even the tossed Namakobushi...
...find it fun!
Plus, the other squishies.
Huh? Can I do Yukihami
and Bachin'uni tossing?!
Whoa!
Wow! Lemme try
a Metamon-Namakobushi toss too!
She’s getting so excited over it...
We didn’t get to squish a Shellder,
but that sure was fun!
I’m glad to hear it.
So what’s the next
rare squishy Pokémon?
It’s Pendrar.
Pendrar!
Wait, that’s a Squipoké?
Yes! The belly of a wild Pendrar
is exquisitely squishy-squishy... so I hear.
Hmm...
The Index doesn’t mention
anything like that, though.
That’s right.
But my exsquishience and insquishition
as a Squisher are shouting it at me!
I see, your experience and intuition
as a Squisher are shouting it at you!
I’m surprised you got that, Liko.
Oh, so I did!
I’m starting to scare myself...
Pendrar!
Just look at that belly!
Doesn’t it look squishable?!
That’s quite the foolish remark
he’s making about you.
Huh?
Who’s that?
Liko?! Navi?!
Roy?! Ult?!
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
You’re acquainted?
Yes, we’re friends.
Oh, but I’ve never met that woman before.
Nice to meet you.
I’m Lalamoo.
Nothing but a simple Hardman.
Hardman?
Uhh...
Oh, a Hardman is a trainer who loves
hard Pokémon, or “Harpokés” for short.
By the way, harnessing your hard fist to dehardmine
whether a Harpoké’s hard is hard enough is called Harding!
Plus, Hardmen have all sorts of rules!
“A true Hardman’s Harpokacts must never leave
a Harpoké with hard feelings,” and so on, and so forth!
Now where have I heard that before?
I see. I get it!
Ms. Lalamoo has the opposite love to
old man Yakata’s love of squishies! She loves hard stuff!
You’re so right.
And as I was enjoying my Harpokacts,
I happened upon dear Roy and dear Ult...
...and invited the pair of them to go
dear-Pendrar-seeking with me!
She was even really complimenting
Ult’s rock collection!
Dear Ult and dear Yamirami’s stones
were just so splendidly hard!
Yer darn right!
You really get me, Lalamoo!
Apparently the back of Loudbone’s jaw
is exquisitely hard, too!
And also, Cap’s presence alone is so hard and cool,
she says he’s the bearer of an exquisite harrit!
Oh, “harrit” means spirit.
Ahem! You spoke of “Pendrar-seeking” earlier,
but why are you seeking Pendrar?
Why, naturally,
because Pendrar’s belly is rock-hard!
My, what a foolish remark you’ve made.
Oh? In what way exactly?
In saying Pendrar’s belly was hard.
But dear Pendrar’s belly is hard, no?
Pendrar’s stomach is squishy!
Oh, it’s quite hard.
No, it’s squishy!
It’s hard.
Squishy!
Hard!
I told you, it’s squishy!
Didn’t I tell you it’s hard?!
Wait, does that mean...?
Could it be...?
Whether Pendrar’s belly is squishy...
...or hard...
...shall be decided by battle!
It’s battle time!
Right this way, Haganail!
Tesseed! Jiodzumu!
Whoa! They all look so hard!
They’re mega-cool!
Let’s go, Namakobushi!
Yukihami! Bachin'uni!
They look really soft!
They’re all squishy!
Now, let’s hartle!
“Hartle”?
That’s probably an abbreviation of
“let’s have a hard Pokémon Battle”!
We’ll show you our squond!
“Squond”?
I think that’s “bond.”
En garde!
Dear Haganail! Heavy Bomber!
Dear Tesseed! Iron Head!
And dear Jiodzumu, use Body Press!
All moves that sound hard!
Yeah!
Namakobushi! Helping Hand!
It’s using Helping Hand weird!
How do you like that squishiness?!
It truly proves that
“foresquished is forearmed”!
Enough of your foolishness!
Once more!
Helping Hand!
Whoa, it happened again!
They’re bouncing off the softness!
You’re not half bad.
I have a question!
Why do you always use the same moves?
My oh my,
that’s quite the foolish question.
I’ve but one reason.
Only the hardest of moves
can make a Hardman’s harrit quake!
I see.
I suspect the reason you insist on
only using Helping Hand is also...
Yes! A battle without squish
would be a sandwich without filling!
For it would be nothing to me!
I thought as much.
Then we shall show you...
...the move Hardmen
can’t get enough of!
Harden!
Then, we too shall deliver
another display of our squishy love!
Use Helping Hand!
Ooh!
My!
Today’s top squish has arrived!
That’s your finest hardness!
Your finest hardness!
Huh?
Hey, you guys...
What’re you doing out here?
They’re having a Pokémon Battle
to decide if Pendrar’s belly is squishy or hard!
Huh?
I suspect that
our difference in opinion...
...is not something
further battling can resolve.
Indeed.
The best resolution in this case...
...is to try touching
dear Pendrar’s belly for reals!
Touch test!
Oh?
It’s not here.
We never did find out if Pendrar’s belly
was squishy or hard, huh?
Yes. But I’ve just decided
on my goal for my next day off!
Right. Next time,
I will get to touch dear Pendrar’s belly!
If you wouldn’t mind...
How about we arrange
to take the same day off?
Very well.
Huh?! They’re getting along!
With you as witness...
I must prove
that Pendrar is a Squipoké.
Dear Pendrar is a Harpoké though,
you know.
They’re kinda weird...
Today was a lot of fun!
There’s really all sorts of people
and all sorts of Pokémon in the world, huh?
There sure are!
That sounds like a whole lotta fun!
Oh! Metamon’s all squishy while it’s awake,
but it’s super hard when it falls asleep!
Can I see?
You’re right!
I get it now!
Squishy and hard...
...I already loved
both of ‘em!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Friede here!
It’s time to Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Today’s topic is Namakobushi!
Namakobushi
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Sea Cucumber Pokémon
Water
Ejecting Innards
A Pokémon that lives where the sea’s shallow,
such as sandy beaches.
Besides their squishy bodies,
do you know what other trait they’re known for?
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
See the answer after the commercials!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Gonna give my motivation button a little tap!
The power of hard work is amazing!
(Ahem!)
But if I slack off I might end up devolving...
Well, that’s no good!
But now you mention it...
I know button mashing won’t help at all
So stop shaking this maiden’s heart already
(Stop it!)
Getting attached, but then they turn away
When things just don’t go the way that you want...
Isn’t it so fun? Doesn’t it make your heart race?
Doesn’t it make you all excited?
When I feel a spark...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
Face to face with the dream I’ve always imagined...
I’ve got electric jolts running through me!
I’m so lovey-dovey I can’t even move!
When I know change is still inside of me...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
then we can be together forever
We’ll conquer any obstacle!
I know our future will shine!
So let’s be friends!
Pick up you! I want you! Hit chu straight in the heart!
Pick up you! I want you! We’re right at the peak of our adven-chu!!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Time to announce
the correct answer!
The answer is...
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
Spinning
Swaying
Being slimy
C: Being slimy!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Step on one by mistake and you’ll trip,
and it might even get mad and punch you back.
Look out!
Huh?
Whoa!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Ow-ow-ow-ow...
Sorry...
Next episode
Today’s the fieldwork day
we’ve been waiting for!
I’ll be with Master!
It’s Navi’s first time meeting him!
Heheh, can’t wait, huh?
Next episode
Hey! Long time, no see!
Friede!
Wait, huh?
Who’s that guy next to you?
Hey! Members of
the Rising Voltteccers!
Next episode
Uhh, umm...
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
The Expanding World, I’ll GO With You!
Now, everyone, GO with cheer!
The Expanding World, I'll GO With You!
Hold on,
at least introduce yourself!